

Europass Curriculum Vitae

Updated September 18, 2018



Personal information

Surname / First name

Address

Telephone

Personal Email

Nationality

Date of birth

Gender

Bio

Buracchi Marco

95, Via Pier Capponi, 50132, Firenze (FI), Italy +39 0575/942167 Mobile: +39 3498362954

ma.buracchi@gmail.com

Italian

19/12/1985

Male

In September 2012 I decided to enroll myself at the University of Florence to pursue my true passion; computer science and cybersecurity. I graduated in October 2015 with 110/110 cum laude and now I am grad student at the master's degree in resilient and secure cyber physical systems, that I expect to obtain in October 2018. My master thesis will be on "Side-Channel Attacks and speculative execution". Before, I graduated from high school in 2004 at IPSIA Margaritone of Arezzo, a professional school for goldsmiths that I attended in parallel to four years of conservatoire (piano). I worked for eight years in the processing of raw materials (gold, silver, steel, wood, plexiglass and fabrics) with CNC machines such as laser cutting, wire EDM and machining center.

Desired employment/ Occupational field

Education and training

Dates

Title of qualification awarded

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

Name and type of organization providing education and training Level in national or international classification

Cybersecurity, Software Development & Research

October 2018 (expected)

Master's degree (Laurea Magistrale) in Resilient and Secure Cyber Physical Systems

Security engineering, Security and network management, Distributed programming for IoT, Multivariate analysis and statistical learning, Coding theory and computer security, Advanced techniques (and tools) for software development, Advanced topics in programming languages, Computer forensics, Models of sequential and concurrent systems, Quantitative analysis of systems, Real-time and critical systems, Systems modeling for verification, Advanced numerical analysis

University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude (expected)

Dates 08/08/2017 - 12/08/2017

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

Name and type of organization providing education and training Cornell, Maryland, Max Planck pre-doctoral research school

Security and privacy, social systems, distributed systems, machine learning, programming languages, and verification

Max Planck institute for software systems, Cornell University, University of Maryland

Dates

01/10/2012 - 09/10/2015

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered Bachelor's Degree (Laurea Triennale) in Computer Science.

Algorithms and data structures, Calculus I and II, Computer architecture, Computer networks, Computing and management, Concurrent programming, Databases and information systems, Discrete mathematics and mathematical logic, Human-Machine interaction, Information retrieval and semantic web technologies, Interpreters and compilers, Linear Algebra, Numerical analysis, Operating systems, Physics, Probability theory and statistics, Programming methodologies, Theoretical computer science

Name and type of organization providing education and training Level in national or international classification

University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude.

Work experience

Dates

01/04/2015 - 01/10/2016

Research helper

Occupation or position held

Main activities and responsibilities I took part in AMADEOS project (Architecture for Multi-criticality Agile Dependable Evolutionary Open System-of-Systems) funded under the European Commission's FP7, supporting research in definition, implementation and evaluation of mechanisms and solutions for the resilient management of the time in the smart grid and smart cities.

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector Prof. Andrea Bondavalli, Resilient Computing Lab, Università di Firenze Research and experimentation of dependable architectures and systems

AutoCAD drawing, CNC programming and cutting (laser, machining center)

Dates

01/05/2008 - 01/09/2012

Occupation or position held Main activities and

responsibilities

Gabry packing, Arezzo, Italy

CNC Machinist and Programmer

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector

Manufacturing industry

Dates

01/05/2006 - 01/05/2008

Occupation or position held

Main activities and responsibilities **CNC Machinist and Programmer** AutoCAD drawing, CNC programming and cutting (laser, machining center, wire EDM)

Name and address of employer

Nuova 230AR, Arezzo, Italy

Gold and jewellery industry

Type of business or sector

01/09/2004 - 01/05/2006 Dates

Occupation or position held

Technical employee

Main activities and responsibilities

Direct measurement in field, fixture designer, autoCAD drawing, cutting programs developer

Name and address of employer

Emmedi srl, Arezzo, Italy Manufacturing industry

Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue Other language(s) Self-assessment European level^(*)

English

Technical skills and competences

Computer skills and competences

Artistic skills and competences

Driving licence(s)

Additional information

Italian

| Understanding | | | | Speaking | | | Writing | | |
|---------------|-----------------|---------|-----------------|--------------------|-----------------|-------------------|-----------------|----|-----------------|
| Listening | | Reading | | Spoken interaction | | Spoken production | | | |
| C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user |

^(*) Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

Good technical skills, especially in cybersecurity, system's safety, computer science

Very good computer skills, learned as self-taught and through the University. Very good knowledge in the use of various programming/markup languages (among the best known: Java, Python, C, Shell Scripting, Assembler, LaTeX, Matlab, R, XML). High expertise with many tools such as Maven, Github, virtualization tools, Docker, test-framework. High skills in managing both software and hardware aspects.

Reasonable level in the use of guitar and in singing. I love skiing and I'm a futsal goalkeeper for more than 10 years

Driver's license (Italian Republic, full European validity), category A (motorcycle owner) and B (car owner).

References

Prof. Michele Boreale, University of Florence, Italy, michele.boreale(AT)unifi.it;

Prof. Rosario Pugliese, University of Florence, Italy, rosario.pugliese(AT)unifi.it;

Prof. Andrea Bondavalli, University of Florence, Italy, andrea.bondavalli(AT)unifi.it;

Personal interests

Computers, Technology, Mathematics, Physics and Science in general. Books, Music and Entertainment. All kind of sports. Travelling around the world.

I hereby authorize the processing of the personal data contained in this CV in compliance with the Italian Personal Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 of 30 June 2003)

Signature: